共犯
第一季  第一集
-开车 -什么 -赶快开车
Drive! What? Just drive!
你个深井冰 是你挑事的 就是你
You crazy twat! You're taking the piss, you!
你个大蠢货 你现在把我们全拉下水了
You stupid prick, you've dropped us all in the shit now,
-你个王八蛋 -到底发生了什么
you stupid bastard! What's happened?!
-你个白痴蠢货 -那是他自找的
You stupid braindead bastard... He was asking for it.
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
-怎么回事 -没什么
What's happened? Nothing.
你现在把我们全拉下水了 你个疯子 蠢蛋
You've dropped us all in the shit now, you crazy twat...
他自找的 自找的
He was asking for it. He was asking for it!
我都让你提防那个混蛋了 不是么
I warned you about this prick, didn't I?!
翻译：酥酥 薇薇  crystal windy  佳佳  VeraS
-到底发生了什么 -什么都没发生
What's happened?! Nothing has happened!
什么都没发生 什么都没发生
Nothing's happened? Nothing's happened?
他只是去刺伤了一个人
He's only gone and stabbed someone,
是吧 愚蠢的疯子 给我闭嘴
hasn't he? Crazy twat. Just shut it.
-什么 -听着 够了 -他刺伤了人 这个愚蠢的疯子
What?! Listen, shut it. He's stabbed someone, the mad twat!
校对：慕斯 Bezero 佳佳
小心我下一秒就会刺你
I'll stab you in a minute, yeah?
-科林 别说了 好么 -你要刺我
Colin, just leave it out, yeah? You'll stab me?!
嘿 嘿 别打了
Hey! Hey, get off him!
开到路边 快开到路边
Pull over! Pull over now!
时轴：络睿 Darren
滚 立马从车上下来 你待在车上
Get out! Get out the car now! You stay there.
冲着我来呗
Come on then!
干嘛 你要干嘛
What? What?
他就是看我不顺眼 对么
He was looking at me, right?!
总监：慕斯 Bezero
-觉得我就像一坨屎 -那个在哪儿 -什么
Looking at me like I'm shit! Where is it? What?!
-刀 你放在哪儿了 -在这儿
The knife. Where is it? It's here.
-把它丢那儿 -这是保罗的 -把它丢到那里
Put it down there. It's our Paul's. Put it down there!
压制：hhjie
他杀了他了么
Did he kill him?
-他杀死他了么 -我不知道
Did you kill him?! I don't know.
-喂 -我是托尼
'Yeah?' It's Tony.
你个混蛋
You bastard!
你让我给你收拾烂摊子 你个混蛋 麦凯布也是
You got off and left me to it, you prick. McCabe as well.
-他怎么样 -我不知道 我都不知道我干了什么
'How is he?' I don't know. I don't know what I'm doing, do I?
据我所知他会失血身亡的 你个混蛋
He could be bleeding to death for all I know, you prick.
-他能活下来么 -可能性不大 不过我怎么会知道
Will he live? 'I very much doubt it, but how would I know?'
你为什么要带那个疯子 恩
Why did you bring that mad bastard, eh?
医疗人员到了
The paramedics are here.
他情况很糟
He's bad.
-糟到什么程度 -我不知道
How bad? Dunno.
但是他不会死的 对吧
But he'll live, though, yeah?
-恩 -开车吧
Eh? Just drive.
沃德太太么 是的
Mrs Ward? Yeah.
托马斯 沃德的母亲
Mother of Thomas Ward?
是的
Yeah.
沃德太太 我们受指令带你去皇家医院
We've been told to bring you down to the Royal, Mrs Ward.
托马斯出了一些小意外
Thomas has had a bit of an accident.
什么意外
What sort of accident?
亲爱的 我不知道 我们只是受命过来接你
I don't know, love. We've just been told to come and get you.
我在染头发
I'm dyeing my hair.
抱歉
Sorry.
给我一分钟
Just a sec.
我的女儿
My daughter.
她花了很多时间筹备婚礼
She spent most of the day getting ready,
她不会很高心的
she's won't be best pleased.
-你好 -你得马上回来
'Hello?' You'll have to come back,
朱莉 照顾一下孩子
Julie, and look after the kids.
-为什么 -托马斯住院了
'Why?' Thomas is in hospital.
你住在那儿多久了
You lived there long?
三年了
Three years.
我们原本住在花园那边 但是后来我们分开了
We used to live by the park but then we split up,
我和孩子父亲 所以我们得找便宜点的地方住
me and their dad, so we had to find somewhere cheaper.
你还见他么
Do you still see him?
只在必要的情况下
Only when I have to.
你好 我是玛格丽特 沃德
Hello. I'm Margaret Ward.
我的儿子托马斯在这儿
My son Thomas is here.
-说姓氏 谢谢 -他应该是出了意外
Surname, please. He's had an accident apparently.
托马斯 沃德
Thomas Ward.
你等一下 我打个电话
If you just hang on, I'll make a call.
詹尼弗 嗨 这里是前台
Jennifer? Hi, it's reception.
沃德太太到了
Mrs Ward is here.
-请问 发生了什么 -沃德太太
What is it, please? Mrs Ward?
-我在找我的儿子 -沃德太太 -托马斯 沃德
I'm looking for my son. Mrs Ward? Thomas Ward.
-沃德太太 -我是詹尼弗 菲尔丁
I'm Jennifer Fielding, Mrs Ward.
-请你跟我来一下 好么 -为什么
Could you come with me, please? Why?
-请跟我来 沃德太太 请 -去哪儿
Come with me, please, Mrs Ward. Please. Where?
这儿过去有一间房间
There's a room just through here.
请进来 沃德太太
Come in, please, Mrs Ward.
请
Please.
我很抱歉 托马斯没有熬过去
Thomas didn't make it, I'm afraid.
熬过什么
Make what?
他今晚早些时候被刺伤了
He was stabbed earlier this evening
在一个小时以前确认死亡
and died just an hour or so ago.
我非常抱歉
I'm really sorry.
我想你可能找错人了
I think you've got the wrong boy.
我是托马斯 沃德的妈妈
I'm Thomas Ward's mother,
而且他只是出了点小意外 就是这样
and he had a bit of an accident, that's all.
他在小林路上的披萨店被刺伤
He was stabbed at the pizza place on Holt Road,
沃德太太 并且到这里一会儿就死了
Mrs Ward, and died here a short time later.
你去哪儿了
Where you been?
-出去玩 -哪儿
Out. Where?
只是出去玩了
Just out.
-和谁 -没有人
Who with? No-one.
-什么 你一个人出去玩 -是啊
What, you went out on your own? Yeah.
-你在说谎 -我没有
You're lying. I'm not!
-你和你爸也打声招呼呀 -我去一下洗手间
Will you talk to this one? I'm going to the toilet.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey!
喂
Hello?
我是詹尼弗 菲尔丁
'This is Jennifer Fielding,
沃德先生 我是皇家医院的社工
Mr Ward. I'm the social worker at the Royal
我有你的儿子托马斯的消息
'and I have some news about your son, Thomas.'
他怎么了
What is it?
您妻子也在这里
'I have your wife...'
是前妻 我让她接电话
..Ex-wife here. I'll pass you over.
嗨
Hi.
他死了
He's dead.
你怎么听这种垃圾
What you listening to that shite for?
披萨店的致命一击
Fatal stabbing at the pizza place.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
电视上放的
On the telly.
他死了么
Is he dead?
都说了致命的 没脑子么 他当然死了
"Fatal", knobhead. Of course he's dead.
他在里面
He's in there.
他们需要有人去辨尸确认
They want someone to identify him.
-什么 你还没确认 -没有
What, you haven't done it? No.
让我来么
Shall I?
只要告诉我那个人不是他就行
Just tell me it's not him.
我和你一起进去吗
Shall I come in with you?
不用了
No.
-已经八点半了 -对啊
It's half eight. Right.
你怎么还在这儿
Why are you still here?
只是在等人
Just waiting for someone.
谁
Who?
基南 吉莱斯皮 你干嘛等那个混蛋
Kieran Gillespie. What are you waiting for that prick for?
我只是想要跟他谈一谈
I just need to speak to him.
谈什么
About what?
-谈什么 -待会见
About what? I'll see you later.
基南 基南
Kieran. Kieran.
他死了
He's dead.
是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
你打算做什么
What are you going to do?
-你得去警察局自首 -什么
You'll have to go to the police. What?!
你得去警察局自首
You'll have to go to the police.
我不会去警察局的 你个蠢蛋
I'm not going to the police, you prick.
如果他们来抓你
It's only going to be worse
结果只会更糟 不是么
if they have to come and get you, innit?
他们为什么会过来抓我 恩
Why are they going to come and get me, eh?
你在说什么 你打算出卖我么
What are you saying? You going to grass me up?
这是你想说的么
Is that what you're saying,
-你打算告发我 -不 我不是说那个
you're going to grass on me? No, I'm not saying that.
-那他们怎么会知道那是我干的 -他们不会的
How are they going to know it's me, then? They won't.
但是他们会知道那是我
But they'll know it's me.
怎么会
How?
车 这是帕特里克的车
The car. It was our Patrick's car.
他们怎么会知道呢
How are they going to know that?
-路边探头 监控器 -那里没有 -有的
Cameras. CCTV. There weren't any. There were.
好吧 他们也只会问你一些问题
All right, yeah, so they'll ask you a few questions.
但是你说什么都不知道 懂么 恩 你不能告发我
But you say nothing, don't you? Eh? You don't grass.
一旦你出卖了我 那么你的死期就到了
If you grass...then you're dead.
而且还不只是你 伙计 远远不止
And more than that, lad, more than that,
如果你告发了的话 如果你泄露给了任何人 恩
if you grass, if you nonce on anyone, yeah,
那么你的母亲会死 你的父亲会死 你的妹妹也会死
then your mum's dead and your dad's dead and your sister's dead
而且你的房子也会被烧掉
and your house is torched.
恩
Yeah?
懂了么 你懂了么 你明白我说的吗
Right? Comprendo? Do you understand what I'm saying to you, yeah?
-是的 是的 -是的 是的
Yeah. Yeah?! Yeah, yeah.
很好
Good.
约翰乔
Johnjo.
发生了什么
What's going on?
发生了什么 约翰乔
What's going on, Johnjo?
约翰乔
Johnjo!
他死了
He's dead.
重大失误 伙计 不要用手机
Major error, mate. Don't use the phone.
你不要用手机联系我 科林 或者基南 明白么
You don't contact me, Colin or Kieran by phone. Right?
明白
'Right.'
我会在工作时候过来见你
I'll come and see you in work.
什么时候
When?
很快了
'Soon.'
W-A-R-D 沃德
W-A-R-D. Ward.
等一下
Hang on a sec.
486 892
486...892.
-还好吗 -是的 老板
All right? Yes, boss.
-今天我不去上班了 -你生病了
I won't be in today. 'Are you ill?'
不 我没生病 没有
No. I'm not ill, no.
那么 理由是什么
'So...what's the problem?'
我的儿子被杀害了
My son's been murdered.
-什么 -我说 我的儿子被杀害了
'What?' I said, my son's been murdered.
你还在么
Are you still there?
是的 好的 额 我会通知他们的
'Yeah, OK... Er, I'll let them know.'
谢谢 我非常感激
Thanks. I'd really appreciate that.
没事 好的 就这样
'Yeah, OK, sure.'
-谢谢 -我非常抱 -谢谢 再见
Thanks. 'I'm really sor...' Thanks. Bye.
额 玛格丽特 沃德 海斯廷斯警官
Er, Margaret Ward, Detective Inspector Hastings.
我非常抱歉 沃德太太
I'm very sorry, Mrs Ward.
谢谢 我们会竭尽所能抓住那群人的
Thanks. We'll do all we can to get these people.
一群人
People?
是的
Yes.
不止一个么
More than one, then?
我们是这么认为的
We think so.
你有个女儿
You've got a daughter.
尼古拉
Nicola.
是的
Yes.
我们是同学
We were at school together.
我去过你家好多次
I stayed in your house loads of times.
玛格丽特 德瓦尼
Margaret...Devaney.
是的 对啊
Then, yeah.
还有一个外号叫 房客罗杰 的
Otherwise known as Roger the Lodger.
是啊
Yeah!
她怎么样 很不错 结婚了么
How is she? Great. Married?
是啊 三个孩子 18岁的男孩和两个
Yeah. Three kids. Boy of 18 and two...
没事的
It's OK.
两个女儿 13和14岁
Two daughters. 13 and 14.
真好
Lovely.
他们一定会落网的 玛格丽特
We'll get them, Margaret.
约翰乔 我对此真是很遗憾 真的 兄弟
I'm sorry about this, Johnjo. I'm really sorry, mate.
-那你打算做点什么  -我不知道
What are we going to do? I don't know.
你会去抓他的对吗
You were going there to get him, weren't you?
是啊 不是那个死掉的小伙子 但是 是的 有那么个人
Yeah. Not the lad who died. But, yeah, someone, yeah.
和披萨店一点关系都没有
Nothing to do with pizzas at all.
不 其他人都知道的 是不是
No. And the others, they knew, didn't they?
是的
Yeah.
除了我之外所有人都知道 对吗
Everyone knew bar me, yeah?
是啊
Yeah.
我可以告诉你我知道的事
I'm telling you the pizza
但这和披萨店没有关系
I want but it's got nothing to do with pizzas
你去那里
because you're going there
-是去解决一群小杂种  -嘘 嘘 嘘
to sort some little bastard out! Sh, sh, sh...
我假装的 我打电话的时候说谎了
I'm made up, aren't I? I'm made up when I get the call.
约翰乔 快来和一群小伙伴吃披萨啊 快来吃披萨
"Johnjo, come for a pizza with the big lads. Come for a pizza..."
-兄弟 别说了 -你为什么不载着我们去吃披萨呢 约翰乔
Shush, mate. "Why don't you drive us for a pizza, Johnjo?"
但是你只对那辆车感兴趣 那辆该死的车
But all you're interested in is the car. The fucking car!
大家都在看咱们
There's people looking over...
伙计 这让我感觉我自己像坨翔一样
That makes me feel like shit, mate,
-并且这都是理所应当的 因为 -拜托 别说了
and so it should, cos... Please, just shut it.
-闭嘴吧你 -因为你就是这么对待我的
Just fucking SHUT IT! Cos that's how you've treated me!
-就像一坨翔一样 你就是这么对待我的
Like shit! That's how you've treated me!
听着 我们是表兄弟 对不
Listen, we're cousins, right?
如果我让我的表兄掉到粪坑了 我会把他拉上来的
If I drop my cousin in shit, I'll get him out of it.
对不
Right?
是的 我们是对你撒谎了 但是你应该感到欣慰
Yeah, we lied to you, but you should be grateful,
因为你可以问心无愧的说
because you can put your
我什么都不知道
hand on your heart and say, "I knew nothing.
"我确实什么都不知道" 我们都会证实你的话
"I knew absolutely nothing." And we'll back you up on that.
我们要确保所有人都知道你是无辜的
We'll make sure everyone knows you're innocent.
我是无辜的 科林是无辜的
I'm innocent, Colin's innocent,
但是你更无辜 不是吗
but you're even more innocent. Right?
-所以 你要告诉他们  -如果我们不得不的时候 我会的
So, what...so you'll tell them? If we have to, yeah.
-你们不得不的时候 一个人都没抓起来呢 难道不是吗
If you have to?! Nobody's been picked up yet, have they?
他们一被抓到 如果他们被抓到了 我们就告诉基南
As soon as they are, if they are, we tell Kieran he's got to
他应该对此负责 向警察承认他是凶手
cough for it, he's got to tell the bizzies it was him.
其他人都没有刀
Nobody else had a knife,
其他人都没有用刀 至少你没有 对吧
nobody else used a knife, least of all you. Right?
约翰乔你什么都不用担心
You've got nothing to worry about, Johnjo. Eh?
能再放大一点吗
Can we get them enhanced?
嗯 我们在努力
Yeah, we're trying.
这是我们能找到的其他三个人最好的图像
This is the best we've got of the other three.
呃 是谁都有可能
Uh. Could be anyone.
-喂 -我是海斯汀斯探长 是你吗 玛格丽特
Hello? DI Hastings here. Is that you, Margaret?
-是 -只是想让你知道我们就快抓到他们了
Yeah. Just letting you know we're arresting someone soon
并且意义重大
and it's significant.
-谁 -再把名字说一下
Who? Name again?
奥谢
O'Shea.
'O'Shea.
你知道些什么吗
'Mean anything?'
不
No.
-所以这跟钱没关系 -没有
So it's nothing to do with money? No.
和上电视也没有关系
And nothing to do with being on telly?
跟那也没有关系
It's nothing to do with that.
就是一群姑娘闯进了足球比赛
It's just some girls are into footie.
-扯淡 -好好说话
Bollocks. Language.
-是足球比赛 对吗 -对
So it's footie, yeah? Yeah.
他们在踢足球
So they play footie, so girls who
所以吸引了那些姑娘们 -对
are into footie are gonna be attracted to 'em? Yeah.
-这就是你的论据 -对
That's your argument, yeah? Yeah.
-我也踢足球 -所以呢
I play footie. So?
所以她们怎么没不可自拔的爱上我
So how comes they're not throwing themselves all over me?
-你最近照过镜子吗 -韦恩 鲁尼照过吗
Have you looked in the mirror lately? Has Wayne Rooney?
我也要弄个和他一样的鸟才行吗
I'm going to get a bird like his, am I,
因为她被足球吸引而我每天都在打游戏
cos she's into football and I play for the Dog and Duck?
那是童年 宝贝
They were childhood sweethearts.
-瞎扯 -我不会再提醒你了
Oh, bollocks! I won't tell you again!
这关乎到名誉和金钱
It's about being famous and
足球能带给你所有
having a load of dosh. Football gives you both.
这跟足球本身没有关系
It's nothing to do with football itself.
这只是得到这样结果的方法
That's just a means to an end.
其他类似的任何事情都可以
It could be anything like that.
唱歌 跳舞 拳击
Singing, dancing, boxing,
都可以为你带来名誉和金钱
anything that brings a bit of fame and fortune.
当然他们会说他们全力以赴
And of course they're gonna say they're into it...
没有人会说
No bird's going to say,
我受不了踢足球但是爱钱
"I can't stand football but I love the dosh."
帕特里克 奥谢
Patrick O'Shea?
-约翰乔 奥谢 -帕特里克在里面吗
Johnjo O'Shea. Is Patrick in?
谁在那儿 约翰乔
Who is it, Johnjo?
那我们就进去了
Yeah. We'll come in then, OK?
谁啊
Who is it?
帕特里克 奥谢
Patrick O'Shea?
-是我 -我们要逮捕你
Yeah? We're arresting you on
-你是托马斯 沃德谋杀案的嫌疑犯 -啥
suspicion of the murder of Thomas Ward. What?
你有权保持沉默
You do not have to say anything.
可如果你一言不发
However, if you do not mention something
-就没有庭证 -这是开玩笑呢对吧
you later rely on in court... This is a joke, isn't it?
可能对你的辩护不利
..It could harm your defence. Anything you do say
你说的都会用作攻击你的证据 你懂吗
may be used in evidence against you. Do you understand?
-这是个玩笑 对吗 -你明白了吗 -不
It's a joke, right? Do you understand? No!
我认为你懂了不过我会再说一次
I think you do but I'll say it again.
-不不不 -我很抱歉 但是这是谋杀案 所以
No, no... And sorry about this, but it's murder, so...
如果你不说些什么作为庭证
If you do not mention something you
可能会对你的辩护不利
later rely on in court it could harm your defence.
-这是昨晚的男孩吗 -是的 -但是他和女朋友在一起
Is this the boy last night? Yes. But he was with his girl!
这样的话就没有什么好担心的
In that case he's got nothing to worry about.
我什么都没做啊
I haven't done anything!
你们弄错了 你们抓错人了
You've got the wrong boy, you've made a mistake!
他什么都没做错 你们要带他去哪
He hasn't done anything wrong! Where are they taking him?
他们把他抓走了 帕特里克
They're arresting him! Patrick!
帕特里克 帕特里克 帕特里克
Patrick! Patrick! Patrick,
发生什么了 爸爸 这是怎么了
what's happening?! Dad, what's going on?
我不知道 他和你说什么了吗
I don't know, did he say anything to you?
他什么都没和我说
He hasn't said anything to me.
帕特里克 给我们打电话
Patrick, call us, all right?
我们可以进去的 告诉我们你在哪儿
We can get in there. Tell us where you are.
帕特里克 发生了什么了 他告诉你什么了吗 -没有 什么都没说
Patrick, what's happening! Did he tell you anything? No, nothing.
擦 我根本不敢相信
Shit. I can't believe it.
不
No!!!!!!
不 不
No! No...
不
No!!!
No!!
-他们放你走了 -我被保释了
They're letting you go...? Police bail.
约翰乔在哪
Where's Johnjo?
他在车里 我们现在真是一头雾水
He's in the car. We're on double yellows.
-到底怎么了 -回家我再告诉你
What's going on? I'll tell you when we get home.
开车 快
Move. Now.
-发生了什么 -我说了 回家再说
What's going on? I've told you. When we get home.
-和约翰乔有关系吗 -是的
Does it involve Johnjo? Yeah.
你觉得这是怎么回事
What do you think it is?
坐下
Sit down.
你现在是在吓唬我吗 帕特里克
You're scaring me now, Patrick.
你什么都不知道 妈妈
You don't know the half of it, Mam.
坐下
Sit down.
我让你坐下
Sit...down.
告诉他们
Tell 'em.
还是我来说
Or shall I tell 'em?
在披萨里面的凶杀案
That stabbing in the pizza place
那些臭小子用了我的车
the lads who did it used my car.
怎么可能
How?
他让他们搭车了
He gave 'em a lift in it.
我在监控录像上看到了 妈妈 -哦我的天
I've seen it on CCTV, Mum. Oh, my God.
-他们 他们告诉我他们要去吃披萨 -哦 约翰乔
They...they told me they were going for a pizza. Oh, Johnjo.
我真想好好揍你一顿 你个小王八犊子
I wish I could smack you, you little prick.
我以为他们是要去吃披萨的
I thought they were going for a pizza!
孩子们都在家
Kids at home?
对
Yeah.
他们怎么样
How are they?
挺开心的
Over the moon.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们偶然遇见过对方
We bumped into each other.
两周以前
Two weeks ago.
他没提到过吗
What, he didn't mention it?
没有
No.
他说什么了吗
Did he speak?
没有
No.
他对我问好
He said hello.
就这样
That was all.
你都不值得他对你问好
"Hello" Was more than you deserved.
我能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you something?
问吧
Yeah.
这是什么
What is it?
你对他说过我坏话吗
Did you have to turn him against me?
-我没有 -你有
I didn't. You did.
我只是告诉了他事实真相
I just told him the truth.
-真相只会让一切都变得更糟糕 -怎么会
The truth was always going to make it worse. How?
你抛弃了我们 怎么会变得更糟糕
You were leaving us. How could it get any worse?
你死了也许会
You dying, maybe.
不 你死了只会变好 因为你死了会带来遗产
No, not even you dying, cos you dying brings in money
抚恤金 保险
pension, insurance.
你离开就让我们变成了穷光蛋
You leaving means we're skint!
你知道这是什么感受吗
You know what it is?
耻辱 和犯罪一样耻辱
Guilt. You feel as guilty as sin.
自你离开之后 你一直都感受到耻辱
Well, you've always felt as guilty as sin, ever since you left,
现在又发生了这种事情
and now THIS.
这比之前还糟糕十倍
This makes it ten times worse.
对不起 我什么都做不了
Well, sorry, nothing I can do for you.
我的孩子受伤了 你看到了吗
My kids were traumatised, you see.
你可能都不知道他是怎么受伤的
You couldn't possibly know how traumatised
因为你正和你的新欢在外面游荡
cos you were off swanning it with your fancy piece.
我看着他 日复一日
I was looking at it day in, day out.
所以我确定他们知道那不是我的错
So I made sure they knew that it wasn't my fault.
而你一直在犯错
And you'd have done the same.
那不是罪恶感
It's not guilt.
嗯 也不全是罪恶感
Well, not...it's not all guilt.
我过去常常幻想我们的重逢
I used to imagine our reconciliation.
他长大以后 我会再遇见他
I'd meet him one day when he was older...
对人有更深的了解之后
..Knew more about men and women, and...
我们去喝一杯
..We'd go for a pint...
像男人一样聊聊天
..And I'd talk to him man to man, you know.
说着残酷的现实
Brutal honesty.
"抓住生命中的幸福"一类的话题
"One life, one shot at happiness," All that stuff.
从此之后 他对我有些妒忌
And after that, he'd have some sort of grudging...
对 不是尊敬
Well, no, not respect, no.
也许是带点妒忌的接受
A grudging acceptance maybe.
我正努力着 你懂得
And I'd build on that, you know.
我正努力着
I'd build on it.
但是他走了
But he's gone.
带着我们重逢的未来一起离开了
And so has the prospect of our reconciliation.
让我感觉
And that makes me so...
-你懂那种感觉 -你敢哭一个试试
You know, it makes me... Don't you dare cry!
你没有哭的权利
You don't have the right.
你哭了 我就
You cry and I'll...
他们 呃 他们需要做一个
They, erm... They can do an
独立的验尸来寻找证据
independent postmortem for defence purposes.
所以 在未来几周你们才能来带走安葬他
So...you'll be able to bury him in the next few weeks.
谢谢
Thanks.
你决定好用哪个棺材了吗
Did you decide which coffin...?
是的 白色的那个
Yeah. The white one.
那个要贵多了
That's rather more expensive.
-没关系的 -如果你有社保 我们能
-It's OK. -If you were on benefits, we could...
一定要那个白色的
It has to be the white one
因为他的朋友想要在上面写下点什么
cos his friends want to write little messages on it.
我会付钱的
I'll get the money.
需要提前付款的 你看
It needs to be up front, you see...
虽然这种时候不应该谈钱 不过
It's hard to talk money at a time like this but...
说实话 没关系的
Honestly, it's OK!
我得到刑事伤害抚恤金 我会用那个付钱
I'll be getting money from Criminal Injuries, so I'll use that.
我觉得它不会及时到帐
I don't think that'll come in time.
-我能不能 -不 他活着的时候你什么也没给我们
-Could I... -No! You gave us nothing when he was alive!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry about this.
现在他死了你也不用这么做
You won't do it now he's dead!
抱歉
I'm sorry...
-明天 -对
-'Tomorrow? -Yeah.'
为什么要等到明天
Why wait till tomorrow?
两个原因 一 他们将会告发他
Two reasons - one, they'll call him a grass.
-什么 -他们将会告发他
What? They'll call him a grass.
-一个男孩被杀了 看在上帝的份上 -我知道
-A boy's just been killed, for God's sake! -I know that.
一个男孩被杀死了 每个人都应该举报凶手
Everyone should be a grass when a boy's been killed.
-我同意 -每个人都应该把他们知道告诉警察
I agree... Everyone should tell the police what they know!
如果这种事发生在我们身上我们也需要这样
That's what we'd want if it happened to us!
-不是每个人都这么想 -我们期待他们讲出实情
-Not everyone sees it that way. -We'd expect them to tell the truth
我同意 但很多人不同意
I agree! But there's loads here who don't!
他们不同意 那边的那些混蛋
They don't. Them mad bastards over there,
他们不这么想
they don't see it like that.
他们会报复我们 因为他举报了他么
They'll burn us out because he's grassed them up.
如果他们没报复我们
And if they don't burn us out,
死的那个孩子的家人会
the family of the lad who died will burn us out.
这是事实
That's the reality!
我们需要一点时间换个住处
We're going to need a bit of time to find somewhere else to live
因为我们会不能住在这里
cos we're not going to be able to live round here.
在他找到律师之前我们什么也做不了
And we can't do anything until he's got a lawyer,
一个正式的刑事律师 周日我们可找不到他们
a proper criminal lawyer, and we won't get one on a Sunday.
-他不需要 -所以我们要等到明天
-He doesn't need one! -So we'll have to wait until tomorrow.
-他当然需要 -他又没做错什么
-Course he needs one! -He's done nothing wrong!
他要做的就是去到儿讲出实情
All he's got to do is go there and tell the truth
因为他不怕讲实话
cos he's got nothing to fear from telling the truth!
为什么要等 他们会这么说
"Why wait?" That's what they'll say.
为什么你们不在刚一知道时就径直过来
"Why didn't you come right round, as soon as you knew?
为什么要躲在律师后面
"And why are you hiding behind a lawyer?
如果没什么需要躲藏的 为什么要等 为什么请律师
"If you've got nothing to hide, why the wait? Why the lawyer?"
-你要去哪 -厕所
-Where are you going? -Toilet.
-我不相信你竟然这么做
-I can't believe you're acting like this.
一个可怜的男孩被谋杀了
Some poor boy's just been murdered!
-我在想约翰乔
-I'm thinking of Johnjo!
-有个可怜的母亲悲痛欲绝
-Some poor mother is off her head with grief
而你却在灵活的应付
and you're ducking and diving!
-我没应付 看在上帝的份上 女人
-I'm not ducking and diving! For God's sake, woman,
我在想我们的儿子
I'm thinking about our son!
-我简直不相信你这么做
-I can't believe you're acting this way!
你怎么了
What's happened to you?!
-海斯廷斯先生吗 -对
Mr Hastings? Yes.
我是约翰乔 奥谢
I'm Johnjo O'Shea.
你逮捕我们帕特里克时去过我家
You came to our house when you arrested our Patrick.
-是我开的门 -嗯
-It was me who opened the door. -Right.
-是我 -对
-It was me. -Right.
是我开的车
It was me who drove the car.
-他们告诉我要去比萨店 -其他人吗 -对
-They told me they were going for a pizza. -The other lads? -Yeah.
-你相信了他们 -是的
-And you believed them? -Yeah.
这样的话 你没什么好怕的 孩子
In that case, you've got nothing to fear, son.
-你只需要把你知道的都告诉我 -我正要说
-You just tell me everything you know and then... -I'm going to.
-然后你会就能回家 好吗 -好
-..You can go back home, OK? -OK.
-你多大了 -17
-How old are you? -17.
你希望你父母在这里吗
Do you want your parents to sit in on this?
-不 -好的
-No. -OK.
-约翰乔有没有可能在你家 -马克太太 我是帕特里克奥谢
Johnjo at yours by any chance? Patrick O'Shea, Mrs Mac.
你家迈克尔在吗
Is your Michael there?
他什么也没说 就这么消失了 他从来不这么做
He didn't say anything, just disappeared. He never does that.
不 伙计 他失踪了
No, he's gone missing, mate.
我们很担心他
We're getting worried about him.
-没事的 我先挂了 -不 我打过他的手机了
-It's OK, I'll hang on. -No, I've tried his mobile.
他不接
He's not answering it.
海斯廷斯警官 简皮尔森警官 和约翰约瑟夫奥谢
DI Hastings, DC Jane Pearson with John Joseph O'Shea.
谈话于2013年6月20日下午一点十八分开始
Interview begins 1:18pm, 20 June 2013.
约翰乔 你记得我问过你希不希望父母在这里
You remember I asked you if you wanted your parents in on this
你说不用
interview, Johnjo, and you said no?
-你记得吗 -记得
-Do you remember that? -Yeah.
嗯 你可以请律师
Well, you can have a lawyer
如果你想的话 这也是你的权利
here if you want. That's your right too.
-你明白吗 -明白
-Do you understand that? -Yeah.
-你需要律师吗 -不 我又没做错什么
-Do you want a lawyer? -No, I've done nothing wrong.
我只是要讲出实情
I'm just telling the truth.
你想接吗
Do you want to answer that?
不
No.
还是语音消息
Still message.
留下你的电话号码 我会给你打过去
'Leave your number and I'll give you a call back.'
约翰乔 我受够了你的胡闹
Johnjo, I'm fed up with you messing about!
我非常担心你 现在给我回电话
I'm worried sick about you! Now phone me!
我哥哥的一个伙伴
One of my brother's mates
给我打电话要我开车送他去比萨店
phoned and asked for a lift to the pizza place.
我说可以 他和另一个朋友一起来了
I said yeah, and he came round with another mate
还有一个叫基兰 吉莱斯皮的人
and a lad called...Kieran Gillespie.
在车里等着
Wait in the car.
-那就是他 -谁 -没什么
-That's him. -Who? -No-one.
我不要带蘑菇的披萨
No mushrooms on mine.
你为什么要这么做
What the fuck did you do that for?!
快上车
Get in the fucking car!
该死的饭桶
Fucking little git!
开车 开车
Drive. Drive!
你个白痴 刹车啊
Fucking stupid! Brake then...
马上就到了 约翰乔
Nearly there now, Johnjo.
我们就还需要一点信息就好了 好吗
Just a few more things we need and then it's over, OK?
另外两个人是谁
Who were the other two lads?
他们没做错什么
They didn't do anything wrong.
我明白 但是我们需要知道他们的名字 约翰乔
I understand that, but we need to know their names, Johnjo.
我不介意告发基兰 吉莱斯皮
I don't mind grassing Kieran Gillespie up,
因为是他捅的人
because he did the stabbing.
但我不会告发另外两个  不会
But I'm not grassing on the other two, no.
他们是你的朋友吗
They your mates?
-不是 -你哥哥的朋友吗
-No. -Your brother's mates?
是的
Yeah.
谁对你来说更重要
Who matters more to you -
他们 还是你父母
them or your parents?
我父母
My parents.
-约翰乔 你说他们在争吵是吗
-You said they were rowing, Johnjo.
你父母 关于你的事
Your parents? Over you.
-是的 关于是不是要去警察局
-Yeah. Over whether to go to the police or not.
是的
Yeah.
这可是坏消息
That's bad news.
你父母可以因此被关进监狱的 约翰乔
Your parents could go to prison for that, Johnjo.
不叫警察 这是在阻碍正义
Not calling the police, that's perverting the course of justice.
即使他们这么做是因为他们爱你
And even if they only did it cos they love you,
这非常非常严重
it's very, very serious.
幸运的是 你来了
Luckily, you've come forward
只要我们从你那里得到全部事实
and as long as we get the whole truth from you,
我们就可以对那些睁一只眼闭一只眼
we should be able to turn a blind eye to all that.
这样很好 不是吗
So it's good, isn't it?
我已经告诉你了 我不会
I've already told you, I'm not...
我不会告发另外两个人
I'm not grassing on the other two.
基兰 吉莱斯皮 可以 另外两个人 不可以
Kieran Gillespie, yeah. The other two, no.
好的
Ok.
你让引擎运转着
You left the engine running.
-是的 -为什么
-Yeah. -Why?
天气很冷
It was cold.
为了快速逃逸吗
For a quick getaway?
不是
No.
我们要不要去找他
Shall we go looking for him?
-开车随便转转 -我们去哪找
-Drive round a bit? -Where would we look?
-我不知道 -如果我们出去时他回来了怎么办
-I don't know. -What if he comes back while we're out?
我就是不能坐在这
I can't just sit round here.
噢 皮特
Oh, Pete!
他怎么了
What's happened to him?
-我们有搜查这个房子的许可 奥谢太太 -什么
-We've got a warrant to search the house, Mrs O'Shea. -What?!
-我们需要搜查这个房子 -你们不是为了约翰乔而来的吗
We need to search the house. You've not come about Johnjo?
我们和约翰乔说话了 并且根据他给我们的信息行事
We spoke to Johnjo, and acting on information he gave us
-我们得到了搜查许可 -他在哪儿
-we obtained a warrant to search the house. -Where is he?
-警察局  介意我进来吗 -我不明白
-Down the station. Do you mind if we come in? -I don't understand.
我进去解释
I'll explain inside.
-发生了什么 -搜查房子
-What's going on? -Searching the house.
我们希望你呆在这个屋子里
We'd like you to stay in this room
马修斯警官会和你呆在一起
and WPC Matthews will stay with you.
我们希望你能试着坐下并放松
We'd like you to try and sit and relax.
当然不要从屋子里拿走任何东西
And certainly don't remove anything from the room.
-如果你需要用洗手间 -你怎么会和约翰乔说话的
-If you need to use the bathroom... -How did you talk to Johnjo?
他去了警察局并作了完整的陈述
He came into the station and made a full statement.
-完整的陈述 -是的
-A full statement? -Yes.
如果他做了完整陈述 你应该知道他什么也没做
If he's made a full statement, you'll know he's done nothing.
如果你想用洗手间
If you want to use the bathroom,
需要有一个警官和你一起去
a police officer will have to go with you.
我们完全确定要拿东西走
We'll almost certainly have to take stuff away,
如果要拿走 我们会拍照
should that happen, we'll photograph it...
我能见见我的儿子吗
Can I see my son, please?
我们需要你见证 并且我们会给你收据
We'll get you to witness it and we'll give you a receipt.
我能见见我的儿子吗 拜托了
Can I see my son, please?!
一旦我能 我就会安排见面
I'll organise that as soon as I can.
我女儿在楼上
My daughter's upstairs!
-你能把她叫下来吗 -凯伦
-Will you get her down, please? -Karen!
我们需要约翰乔那天晚上穿的衣服
We'll need the clothes Johnjo was wearing that night.
凯伦 下来
Karen, get down here!
怎么
What's going on?
它们在篮子里
They'll be in the basket.
他穿着牛仔裤 袜子
He's wearing the jeans. Socks,
背心和内衣在篮子里
vest and undies will be in the basket.
-妈妈 -下来
-Mum? -Get down here!
怎么了
What's going on?
他们在搜查房子
They're searching the house.
-到这儿来 -看在上帝份儿上
-Get in here. -For God's sake...
看右边
Look right.
看左边
Look left.
我们比那个要好 来吧
We're better than that. Come on.
希拉阿姨
Auntie Shelagh.
-是真的吗 -什么是真的吗
-Is it true? -Is what true?
-警察搜查了你的房子 -是的
-Police searched your house. -Yeah.
-她知道吗 -不
-Does she know? -No.
-他们在找什么
-What were they looking for?
-证据 -什么证据
-Evidence. -About what?
如果你不告诉她 我会
If you don't tell her, I will.
什么
What?
什么证据
What is it?
比萨店捅人的事
That stabbing in the pizza place.
什么
Yeah?
约翰乔开的车
Johnjo drove them.
是基兰 吉莱斯皮
It were Kieran...Gillespie.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
你怎么会知道
How do you know that?
我和他
I was with him.
你利用了他 是不是
You used him, didn't you?
我们的约翰乔
Our Johnjo.
-不 伙计 -就是你干的
-No, mate. -You did.
你知道他是什么样的人
You know the kind of lad he is.
你还知道 你放个屁他都觉得是香的
You know he thinks the sun shines out of your arse.
他从来不会拒绝你
He was never going to say no to you.
不 伙计 我们一开始就试着联系你 但你手机关机了
No, mate. We tried you first, your phone were off.
对不起 妈妈
I'm sorry, Mum.
他们说不会放我走的
They said they won't let me go.
一个晚上而已 约翰乔
It's only for one night, Johnjo.
只是一晚而已
Just one night.
明天 我们去法庭
And tomorrow, we go to court,
我们会告诉他们你什么也没干
we tell them you've done nothing,
我们会让你出来 然后带你回家
we get you out and we bring you home.
好的
Right.
我保证
I promise.
夫人 我们基于三个原因 请求保释
'We ask for bail on three counts, Ma'am.'
第一 他只有十七岁
One, he's 17 years of age.
第二 他是个品行无可挑剔的年轻人
Two, he's a young man of impeccable character,
没有任何前科
no previous convictions whatsoever.
第三 他出于自愿 走进警局
Three, he walked into the police station of his own accord
做出了完整和坦率的自白
and gave a full and frank statement.
正是因此 他今天才会站在你面前
And that is the only reason he stands before you today.
请
Yes?
我们反对保释 女士 因为指控罪行性质严重
We oppose bail, Ma'am, due to the serious nature of the charge.
保释被拒绝
Bail refused.
你将拘留两周时间候审
You are remanded in custody to reappear here in two weeks' time.
带他下去
Take him down.
这里有些文件被弄混了
There's been a mix up with the paperwork...
-不好意思 -具体是哪些 -不好意思 法官大人
-Excuse me. -Can you be more specific? -Excuse me, please!
怎么了
Yes?
-你还好吗 奥谢先生 -他是血友病患者
-Are you OK, Mr O'Shea? -He's a haemophiliac!
哦 好吧 我会确保有人照顾他的 别担心
Oh. Well, I'll make sure he's looked after, don't worry.
请带他下去
Take him down, please.
4600磅
4,600.
是的
Yes.
嗯 我有段时间没接触这些了
Well, I don't have any recent experience,
但对于一个丧礼来说是不是花费太大了
but isn't that's a lot for a funeral?
是有一点超出平均水平了
It's a bit more than average, yes.
你在我们这儿已经透支 呃 好几次了
Well, you've had an overdraft with us for...quite some time
而你还拖欠着房屋抵押贷款
and your mortgage is still in arrears,
显然你目前有些困窘了
so you've obviously struggled.
除非你的处境得到彻底的改善
Unless your personal circumstances have radically improved,
否则我可不认为再欠什么外债是明智之举
then I just don't think it's wise to take on any more debt.
对不起
Sorry.
但我的处境已经改善了
But they have improved.
-彻底地改善 -怎么做到的
-Radically improved. -How?
我少了一个要养活的人
I have one less mouth to feed.
不好意思 打扰到你我很抱歉
Sorry about that. And I'm sorry to have bothered you.
这是你们三个有目的性地
And now the three of you walking purposefully
从车走到卖披萨的地方
from the car to the pizza place.
在那儿的是你 基南 对吗
That is you there, Kieran, yeah?
无可奉告
No comment.
你说你是进去买披萨的 那大概需要20分钟
You say you went in for a pizza, but that could be 20 minutes.
-但为什么车没有熄火 -无可奉告
-Why leave the engine running? -No comment.
之后你们出来了 却变得惊慌失措
And now you're out again, panicking.
你是这么说的吧 惊慌失措 对不对 柯林
You'd call that panicking, wouldn't you, Colin?
那儿 你冲着基兰吉莱斯皮大吼
There, you're shouting at Kieran Gillespie.
-你为什么要冲着他吼 -无可奉告
-Why are you shouting at him? -No comment.
-你好 -怎么了
-Hiya. -All right?
我只是路过 或许可以送你一程
I'm just passing, I thought I'd give you a lift.
到哪儿
Where?
嫌犯指认程序
ID parade.
-我们为什么停在这儿 -他的妈妈住在这 -谁的妈妈
-Why are we stopping here? -His mother lives here. -Whose?
那个被刺伤的男孩的
Boy who got stabbed.
她有话对你说
She's got something to say to you.
你好 玛格丽特 这是玛格丽特 沃德 这是雨果 戴维斯 -你好 -你好
Hi, Margaret. Margaret Ward, this is Hugo Davies. -Hello. -Hello.
-那个披萨店是他经营的 -噢
-He runs the pizza place. -Oh!
我想谢谢你 雨果
I wanted to thank you, Hugo.
谢谢你及时给救护车打电话
Thank you for phoning the ambulance so promptly,
给了我儿子最大的可能逃过这一劫
for giving my son his best chance of survival.
虽然当时你可能不知道 但
It wasn't meant to be, but...
谢谢你
Thank you.
我今晚给你打电话
I'll phone you tonight.
我们认为在谋杀的那个晚上
'We think one of the three men who entered your shop
走进你店里的三人之一 就在这个辨认范围之中
'on the night of the murder is in this line-up.'
请你看看能否辨认出其中之一吗
Can you see if you recognise anyone, please?
没有
No.
-你确定吗 -是的
-Are you sure? -Yeah.
好的 那
Right, well...
再一个
One more.
再次 请看看能否认出任何一个
Again, see if you can recognise anyone, please.
没有
No.
-你想再看一遍吗 -不了
-Do you want to see them again? -No.
你辨认得很快啊
You were very quick, you see.
我当警察当了33年
I've been a copper now for
从没见过什么人能辨认得这么快
33 years and I've never seen anyone as quick.
除非你是不想指认出任何人
It was if you didn't want to recognise anyone.
对不起
Sorry.
现在道歉还早 孩子
You will be, son.
你甚至没有认出托尼 华莱士
You didn't even recognise Tony Wallace.
-谁是托尼 华莱士 -你不知道托尼 华莱士吗 -不
-Who is Tony Wallace? -You don't know Tony Wallace? -No.
我们查了你店里呼进呼出的电话
We've checked the calls made to and from your shop.
在谋杀15分钟前你给他打了电话
You phoned him 15 minutes before the murder.
他立即就给你回电了
He phoned you immediately after it.
请为我找个律师
I'd like a lawyer, please.
好的
Yeah.
我能为我儿子做的不多
There is very little I can do for my son.
但我能给他一个好的送行 一个好的葬礼
But I can give him a good sendoff, a good funeral.
我无论如何也要5000英镑
I'm getting ??5,000 anyway.
我并不是想要钱 只是我必须得到这么多
I don't want it, but I'm getting it.
所以请现在就给我钱 然后我就能埋葬他了
So give me it now and then I can bury him with it.
我们将尽快处理此事 华德太太
We'll speed things through as much as possible, Mrs Ward,
但 在葬礼之前我们不能保证付款
but...I can't promise payment before the funeral.
那 那我要怎么葬我的儿子
Well, then, how do I bury my son?
那么你对我的客户的指控是
And what are you charging my client with?
-谋杀 -什么 -联合谋杀 -真荒唐
-Murder. -What? -Joint enterprise murder. -That's ridiculous!
难道不是吗
Isn't it?
当我没说
No.
胃酸过多导致的消化不良 使我牙齿上的珐琅质都流失了
Acid indigestion. It's taking the enamel off my teeth.
-鬼知道我的胃到底怎么了 -过去一段时间
-God knows what it's doing to my stomach. -In the old days,
我们一直努力寻找究竟是谁动了刀子
we worked hard to establish who it was who used the knife.
而他将因谋杀获罪 其他的人则是自由之身
He'd get done for murder and the other scumbags would go free.
我以为 这些功夫会使得那些卑鄙的人逍遥法外
All that effort, I used to think, just so scumbags could go free.
而现在一切都改变了
Well, now it's all changed.
我们不再需要证明是谁用了刀
We don't have to prove who used the knife any more...
因为你们都会因为谋杀获罪
..Cos you all get done for murder.
如果你在那儿 怂恿他了
If you were there, egging him on,
掩护他 以任何方式帮助了他
backing him up, helping in any way...
比如一个电话 一个会心的眼神 甚至
..A phone call, a knowing look, even...
你就可以因为谋杀而定罪
..You get done for murder.
这就是所谓的联合谋杀 雨果 而我特别喜欢它
It's called joint enterprise, Hugo, and I love it.
是的
Yes.
有什么是我们能帮你的吗
Is there anything we can help you with,
-探长 -当然有了
-Detective Inspector? -Yeah.
他可以做一个完整的申明 指认嫌疑人
He can make a full statement, name names
并且如有必要的话 同意提供证据
and agree to give evidence, if necessary.
那么回报是
And in return?
他得到自由
He goes free.
那时候只有我一个人
'I was on my own.
差不多8点时晚餐点就过了 但是10点左右人又多起来了
'It dies off about eight, you see, picks up again at about ten.'
你好
'Hello?'
-托尼 我是雨果 戴维斯 -你没事吧
-Hugo Davies here, Tony. -‘You all right?'
你还在艾尔比弗拉纳根那个蠢货那儿工作吗
You still after that gobshite Albie Flanagan?
是的 伙计
'Yes, mate, too right.'
是的 他刚打电话要了三个特色披萨
Yeah, he's just phoned for three specials.
-哦 真是凑巧 我两分钟后就到 -好吧 伙计
-‘Yeah, spot on. Be down in two.' -OK, mate.
我经常去看足球比赛
I go to the match.
也会看到边裁
I see linesmen.
他们并不能确定是否有人越位
They're unsure whether a man's offside or not,
但他们还是会举起旗帜
but they put the flag up.
十之八九 他们举旗
Nine times out of ten, they put the flag up.
是因为他们想被重视
Because they want to be seen to matter.
而一个人被重视
And you're seen to matter
且蛭乃撬牟凰?
if you do something, not when you don't.
我想这就是我为什么打电话
I think that's why I made the call.
而我那时想要被重视
'I wanted to be seen to matter.'
-嘿 雨果 -嗨 艾尔比 你怎么样 -还不错吧
-All right, Hugo? -All right, Albie? -How's it going? -Sound.
-你在这工作多久了 -几个月吧 -这工作到底有什么好的
-How long have you been here? -A few months. -Is it any good?
不算坏吧
Yeah, it's not bad.
噢
Oh!
-别在这儿动手 -你再敢碰她一下
-Not in here! -Touch her
-我就杀了你 听清楚了吗 -出去 托尼
-again and I'll kill you, right? -Outside! Tony!
-把他带出去 听到没 一切都乱套了 托尼
-Get him out! You got me, yeah? This is out of order, this, Tony!
完全乱套了
This is completely out of order!
你们会把警察招来我的店里的 托尼 这样不行
This'll bring the coppers round my shop! That's not right, Tony!
-我要把你揍得屁滚尿流 -把他带出去
-I’ll go on knocking the shit out of you. -Take him outside.
-你在看什么 -没什么
-What are you looking at? -Nothing.
你以为我是脑残吗 我马上就做掉你
You think I'm shit? I'll kill you, right?
足够了 伙计
He's had enough now, mate.
托尼 给我滚出我的店 马上
Tony, get the fuck out of my shop Tony, now!
我问你呢
I said,
-你觉得我是脑残吗  -不
do you think I'm shit?! No.
-带他出去 -冷静点 伙计 天塌下来我担着呢
-Get him outside! -Chill out, mate. It's all going to be on me...
如果我知道你会在这儿动手
If I had known you would do it here,
就不会给你打电话 哥们儿
I'd have never have rung you, mate!
他捅了他
He's stabbed him.
那个混蛋脑残捅了他
The mad bastard's stabbed him!
-老天啊 基南 我就知道会发生这种事 -你脑子坏了吗
-Jesus, Kieran... I knew this would happen. -You mad bastard!
你这个蠢货 疯子
You stupid mad bastard!
他妈的
Fucking...
有人被刺伤了
..Someone's been stabbed.
-我不知道自己在做什么 伙计 -拜托
-I don't know what I'm doing, mate. -Please.
超波披萨店 在转角处 超波披萨店
Superbo Pizza, it's on the corner. Superbo Pizza.
那个王八蛋已经离开了 霍尔特路 H-O-L-T 霍尔特
The bastard's gone off without him. Holt Road. H-O-L-T. Holt.
他们全都逃跑了 只剩下我对着那个人
They all just got off and left me to it,
那个被刺伤的人 就是埃文 柯林 麦凯布动的手
the pricks. Even Colin McCabe.
埃文 柯林 麦凯布
Even Colin McCabe?
是的 他是一个护士
Yeah, he's a nurse.
-你好 -是我
- Hello? - 'It's me.'
-你好吗 -好极了
-How are you? -‘Fine.'
怎么了
'What is it?'
我拿不出钱来安葬他
I can't get the money to bury him.
我给你 可以吗
'Can I give you it?'
好的
Yeah.
多少
How much?
4600磅
'4,600.
可能还要200 用来就餐
'And maybe 200 for the buffet.
四千八
'Four-eight.'
明天我带五千来找你吧
I'll bring round five grand tomorrow.
四千八就好
Four-eight.
好的 四千八
谢谢
Thanks.
对不起 我对你态度太差了
I'm sorry for treating you so badly.
还撒了谎 对不起
I'm sorry for lying...
我只是想要钱 汤米
I just want the money, Tommy.
好吧
Right.
他来了 妈妈
He's here, Mum.
你在妇女中受赞颂
Blessed art thou amongst women
你的亲子耶稣同受赞颂
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
圣母玛利亚 上帝之母 为我们罪人祈求天主
Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners now
在我们弥留之际
and at the hour of our death.
阿门
Amen.
万福玛利亚 你充满圣宠 主与你同在
Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord is with thee.
你在妇女中受赞颂
Blessed art thou amongst women,
你的亲子耶稣同受赞颂
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
圣母玛利亚 上帝之母 为我们罪人祈求天主
Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners,
在我们弥留之际
now and at the hour of our death.
阿门 万福玛利亚 你充满圣宠
Amen. Hail Mary, full of grace.
主与你同在
The Lord is with thee.
你在妇女中受赞颂
Blessed art thou amongst women,
你的亲子耶稣同受赞颂
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
万福玛利亚 上帝之母
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
为我们罪人祈求天主 在我们弥留之际
pray for us sinners, now and at the hour of our death.
阿门
Amen.
万福玛利亚 你充满圣宠 主与你同在
Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord is with thee.
你在妇女中受赞颂
Blessed art thou amongst women,
你的亲子耶稣同受赞颂
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
万福玛利亚 上帝之母 为我们罪人祈求天主
Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for us sinners...
你也没进去啊
Not into that either?
我们很幸运 有个好法官
We've been lucky. We have a good judge.
我准备要求他
I'm going to ask him to
将此当成一件简单的谋杀案来看待
view it as a straightforward murder case -
一个杀手 一个受害者 没有帮凶
one killer, one victim, not joint enterprise.
如果他同意这样 如果他认同
And if he agrees to that? If he agrees to that,
约翰乔就可以回到你身边
then JohnJo's coming home with you.
无论发生什么
No doubt whatsoever.
基兰 吉莱斯皮
Kieran Gillespie,
你被控告以谋杀 托马斯 詹姆斯 沃德
you are accused of the murder of Thomas James Ward.
你如何辩护
How do you plead?
无罪
Not guilty.
科林 麦凯布 你被控告以谋杀 托马斯 詹姆斯 沃德
Colin McCabe, you are accused of the murder of Thomas James Ward.
你如何辩护 无罪
How do you plead? Not guilty.
安东尼 华莱士 你被
Anthony Wallace, you are
控告以谋杀 托马斯 詹姆斯 沃德
accused of the murder of Thomas James Ward.
你如何辩护 无罪
How do you plead? Not guilty.
约翰 约瑟夫 奥谢 你被
John Joseph O'Shea, you are
控告以谋杀 托马斯 詹姆斯 沃德
accused of the murder of Thomas James Ward.
你如何辩护
How do you plead?
无罪 请坐下
Not guilty. Be seated.
我将听取意见书 然后进行午餐休息 之后后我将给予回复
I'll hear submissions, we'll break and I'll respond after lunch.
谁先来 巴尔内斯 威廉姆斯先生
Who will go first? Mr Barnes-Williams?
我代表约翰 约瑟夫
I represent John Joseph
奥谢 并列出了四条辩护重点 法官大人
O'Shea and I make four main points, your honour.
首先 四个年轻人在此被诉为凶手
First, four young men stand accused of murder.
只有其中一人使用了凶器
Only one of them wielded the knife
到现在为止诉讼方
and yet the prosecution
也没有试图去辨认谁才是持刀者
will make no attempt to identify that man.
不需要这样去做是因为诉讼方认定被告为伙同犯罪
It need not do so because of Joint Enterprise.
伙同犯罪 或共同目的的犯罪
Joint Enterprise, or Common Purpose,
于18世纪被列入宪法
a law introduced in the 18th century
原用于阻止贵族间的决斗 现在更多的
to stop the aristocracy from duelling, is now being used
用于防止审判不公
increasingly against young people from our council estates.
却太多的造成了现在这种结果
And all too often it results in cases such as this,
让一个年轻人 被质疑有罪 被给与罪名
where a young man, who is asked for a lift, gives that lift
且可能为此面临终身监禁
and faces life in prison for it.
第二 我主张
Secondly, I would submit
对于伙同犯罪的发生
that for a joint enterprise murder case to
所有的关系人需要面临审讯
proceed, all those involved in the enterprise must face trial.
但在这场案件中 法官大人
But in this case, your honour,
有一个人不同 就是披萨店经理 雨果 戴维斯先生
one person does not, that is the pizza manager, Mr Hugo Davies.
现在你可以质疑他是否牵连
Now it could be argued that his involvement
于这所有的关键联系人
in all of this was vital,
在这一切发生之后是他当面警告其中一个年轻人人
after all it was he who alerted one young man to the fact that
另一个青年人 他的宿敌 即将到达这家店
another young man, his sworn enemy, would shortly be in the shop.
那么 为什么雨果 戴维斯先生能够逃脱审判
So why does Hugo Davies escape trial
与这相比 剩余的几个年轻人更应该被无罪释放
when those who are far less guilty, face it?
当然他在码头的缺席意味着仅有一个人
Surely his absence from the dock means that only one man
可以被确切的认为参与犯罪
can be held responsible for this crime and, again, it is
就是那个持刀者
he who wielded the knife.
第三 他们在这场案件中并不是伙同犯罪
Thirdly, there was no joint enterprise to murder the victim,
案件没有计划  没有阴谋
there was no planning, there was no conspiracy.
最多也就是 安东尼 华莱士想去
At worst, Anthony Wallace went
披萨店见埃尔比 弗拉纳根
to the pizza shop to confront Albie Flanagan.
在这起斗争事件中 一个年轻人
During the course of that confrontation, a young man,
汤玛斯 沃德 一个无辜的旁观者 被刺伤
Thomas Ward, an innocent bystander, was stabbed.
但之中没有人是故意进入店中去伤害汤玛斯 沃德的
But nobody entered the shop intent on harming Thomas Ward.
他的死亡源于无理智
His murder was just a moment of madness.
无计划 不假思索的暴力
With no forethought and no plan.
因此 我强调 只有确切的责任人
So, again, only he who was responsible for this
那个持刀者 需要接受审判
moment of madness, he who wielded the knife, should face trial.
无辜者应被释放
And the innocent should go free.
第四 综上所诉 我的委托人
And fourthly, with specific reference to my client
约翰 约瑟夫 奥谢
John Joseph O'Shea.
他只是驱车带别人去买披萨
He will simply say that he drove the others for a pizza
没有用证据能够反驳这一事实
and there is no evidence to disprove that.
更何况 他没有
Furthermore, he didn't
同其他人一起进入商店里面 甚至在案件发生时
go into the shop with them so he wasn't even
他都没有出现在犯罪现场
on the scene of the crime when the crime was committed.
我主张不能冒险对其审判
I submit it would be dangerous to proceed against him
尤其是在这样单薄的证明下
on such a flimsy basis.
连带责任可能比较合理 法官大人
Joint enterprise might allow it, your honour.
正义不允许冤枉无辜
Natural justice should not.
感谢陈述 下一位 科特先生
Thank you. Next? Mr Cotting?
法官大人 我代表
Your honour, I represent...
你介意让我们坐在这里么
Would you like us to sit somewhere else?
介意
Yes.
我们的儿子是无辜的 沃德小姐
Our son is innocent, Mrs Ward...
请离开  我们马上就走
Please, go. We're going.
我只想让你知道他说的是实话 他是无辜的
I just want you to know he's telling the truth, he's innocent.
无辜 是的
Innocent? Yes.
那他为什么不立刻报警
Then why didn't he phone the police immediately?
因为他的头被
Because his head was all...
他的头 我儿子的头呢
His head? What about mine?
在此基础上 此案件
'And on that basis alone, the case'
科林 麦凯布应该听说过
against Colin McCabe should be heard.
最终 约翰 约瑟夫 奥谢
Finally, John Joseph O'Shea.
你提出的第一点 巴尔内斯 威廉姆斯先生
Your first point, Mr Barnes-Williams,
似乎是想表达 你不喜欢合伙犯罪这个概念
seems to be this - you do not like joint enterprise.
但是 对于此我能做的不多
However, there is little I can do about that.
这不是议会 我们不能修改
This is not parliament. We can't amend,
起草 或 发布法令
create or abolish any law.
法律中关于伙同犯罪的认定是存在的  政府决定
The law of joint enterprise exists, the crown has decided to
就此法令判罚 因此我有责任听从
prosecute according to that law so it is my duty to hear it.
现在 你的第二主张的分量更重
Now your second submission carries more weight.
如果有五个人被牵涉到一场团伙犯罪
If there are five people involved in a joint enterprise,
这所有的五人应当共同站在审判席上
all five should stand trial.
但事实并非如此
That is not happening here.
只有四人于此接受审判
Only four of the five face charges
第五位却是原告证人
and the fifth is a witness for the prosecution.
请放心 当考虑他的证词是
Rest assured, I will ask the jury to keep that in mind
我将要求陪审团记住这一点
when weighing his evidence.
我知道不是完美 但是总比没有的好
I know that is not perfect but it is better than nothing.
正义降临在四人身上当然比没有正义更好
Justice for four is surely better than justice for none.
现在 你说从来没有
Now, you say there was never
任何针对攻击托马斯 沃德的阴谋或计划
any conspiracy or plan to attack Thomas Ward.
是正确的
That's correct.
但确实有一个计划袭击一位名叫阿尔伯特 弗拉纳根的年轻人
But there was a plan to attack a young man named Albert Flanagan
在攻击的过程中 托马斯 沃德去世了
and in the course of that attack, Thomas Ward died.
他是预定目标或一个无辜的旁观者
Whether he was the intended target or an innocent bystander is
已无从得知 但这仍是合谋杀害
immaterial, it is still joint enterprise murder.
最后 您将对您委托人指控的证据 描述为
Finally, you describe the case against your client as
单薄的  他没有
"Flimsy" In that he didn't
进入商店而是在车里坐着等待
enter the shop but sat waiting in the car.
但这并没有削弱案件中对他的指责
But this doesn't necessarily weaken the case against him.
反而加强了它
It could strengthen it.
控方可以说约翰约瑟夫 奥谢是
The prosecution could argue that John Joseph O'Shea was
个载凶手逃跑的司机
a getaway driver.
一个没有直接参与犯罪的司机
And a getaway driver does not participate in the crime,
他坐一辆发动机仍在运行的汽车里
he sits in the car with the engine running.
总的来说 我认为这是正确的
On balance I think it right
让陪审团来考虑这种可能性
for the jury to consider that possibility.
我相信
I'm confident that the case
对所有四个被告应继续审判
against all four defendants should proceed.
你将不得不认罪 基兰
You're going to have to plead guilty, Kieran.
-那是你至少可以做的 -没门 -请承担责任
-That's the least you can do. -No way. -Take the blame.
你就是那个让我们掉入泥沼的人
You're the one who dropped us in this shit.
没门 什么 你认为你可以撇清这些
No way! What, you think you can get away with it?
是的 我确定 是的 你该这样
Yeah, I do. Yeah. You've got
你不会有机会摆脱这些 你这个臭混蛋
no chance of getting away with it, you prick.
他把一切都告诉他们 雨果告诉了他们一切
He's told them everything. Hugo's told them everything.
一旦我们表明了立场
When we take the stand,
我们会告诉他们一切 你已经没有机会全身而退
we'll tell them everything. You've got no chance.
-你要告密 -当然我们要上报
-You're gonna grass? -Of course we're going to grass.
你刺伤的别人 你出的手
You stabbed someone, you knob!
你要告诉他们它是你 只有你
You're going to have to tell them it were you. Just you.
对吗 我们对它一无所知 我们对这把刀一无所知
Right? We knew nothing about it. We knew nothing about a knife.
对么
Right?
然后我将会失去自由
And I'll go down for life.
无论如何你都不会得到自由 因为你不能摆脱这些
You'll get life anyway cos you can't get away with it.
-让我们走着瞧 -不 兄弟
-We'll see. -No, mate.
如果你将我们都拖进监狱
You take us down with you,
你在监狱里 日子也不会好过的
your life won't be worth living inside.
我会修理你的 如果我不这样做 其他人也会的
I'll get to you. And if I don't, someone else will.
你会生不如死地一天天数日子
You'll be doing life and you'll cacking it every single day.
他们会把你跟强奸犯放在一起
They'll put you with the nonces.
你将会终其一生同强奸犯共同生活
You'll be doing life with the nonces
除非你说出真相 承担责任 兄弟
unless you tell the truth and take the blame, mate.
说出真相 基兰
Tell the truth, Kieran.
认罪 你将会成为英雄 你不想么
Go on, you'll be a hero, then, won't you?
基兰吉莱斯皮承认谋杀
"There's Kieran Gillespie who pleaded guilty to murder
因此他的同伴将会被无罪释放
"So his mates could go free.
他是一个很好的小伙子
"He's a good lad him."
我告诉我妈妈我没有这样做
I told my mum I didn't do it.
好吧
All right.
好吧 我会认罪的 是的
OK. I'll do it, yeah.
我会这样做的 我要跟谁说
I'll do it. Who do I tell?
-法官 还是别的什么人 -不 你要告诉公诉方 我带你去
The judge? What? No, you tell the prosecution. I'll do it.
我认识他
I know him.
-我恐怕你们不能这么做 -不能么 -法官会说
-No can do, I'm afraid. -No? -The judge will say,
吉莱斯皮先生的生活本就
"Mr Gillespie's getting life anyway.
一无所有 所以当然他会尽力
"He's got nothing to lose, so of course he's going try to
承担所有责难让其同伙脱罪
"Get his mates off by taking all the blame."
-所以呢 你能接受的是 -吉莱斯皮先生承认谋杀
-So what will you accept? -Mr Gillespie pleads guilty to murder,
另外三人重度伤害或合谋重度伤害
the other three to GBH or conspiracy to commit GBH.
然后会受刑
What'll that get us?
十年
Ten years.
没必要十年
Nowhere near ten years.
刑罚标准是这样 但法官将会考虑
The tariff starts there but the judge will
在下班后给以认罪答辩时间 时间不能提前
knock off time for a guilty plea, time off for no previous.
在最坏的情况下 在最坏的情况下 六年
At worst, at the very worst, six years.
我们没有做任何事情
We've done nothing!
我们有做任何事
I've done nothing.
他没做任何事 他所做的更少
He's done nothing and he's done even less!
对不起 但你需要提供些什么否则你现在
I'm sorry but you either take what's on offer or you all
正在受着联合谋杀的审判
stand trial for joint enterprise murder.
我可以自己受审吗
Could I stand trial on my own?
恐怕不能
Afraid not.
接受六年或者冒着生命危险去辩护 是的
Take six years or risk life? Yeah.
喂 什么 他该怎么办
Well? What? What does he do?
我不知道 你觉得他该怎么做
I dunno. What do you think he should do?
我不知道
I don't know!
你不可能逍遥法外的 什么 你知道的
You're not getting away with it. What? You know what.
之前你从没做过决定
You've never made a decision in your entire life...
-是你不让我做决定 -你现在必须做决定了
-You've never let me! -You have to make one now!
你觉得他该做什么
What do you think he should do?
-我说了 我不知道 -你知道
-I told you, I dunno! -You do,
但是你不说 你想要我们做选择
but you won't say. You want us to choose.
如果我们选择承认是共犯 他就能活下来 你就可以责备我们
We choose wrong, he gets life, you blame us.
我们要被判6年
We take the six years, you
你为了这个怪我们 这个你都不关心的东西
blame us for that as well, well no, you're not on.
你告诉我们 你觉得他应该怎么做
You tell us what you think he should do.
-坐6年牢 -坐6年牢么
-Take the six years. -Take the six years?
-你能坐6年牢吗 -你在巴特林连一周都待不下去
-Could you do six years? -Couldn't do a week in Butlins.
我可以
I could do six years.
尽管这不仅是6年的问题 对吗
It's not just six years though, is it?
-你得承认这个男孩的死 你占了很大因素 -而我没有
-You'd be saying you played a part in that boy's death. -I didn't.
我知道
I know.
妈妈 我无法认罪 随他们怎么做
I'm pleading guilty to nothing, Mum. They can do what they want.
嗨 家里现在没人 请留言
"Hi, we're not at home. Please leave a message."
嗨 我是希拉 我又打来了
'Hi, it's Sheila, again.
我知道你们在家 能接一下电话吗
'I know you're there, will you just pick up?
如果你们不接电话 我等下就过去
'If you don't pick up, I'm coming round.
我马上过去
'I'm coming round.'
是希拉
There's Sheila.
你在浪费时间 我不会
You're wasting your time! I am not
允许我的儿子承认什么莫须有的罪名
letting my son plead guilty to something he didn't do!
你宁可他因谋杀罪而被审判吗 是的
You'd sooner him stand trial for murder? Yes!
你以为他是在脱罪吗
You think he'll get off with it, don't you?
没有人想要脱罪 他是无辜的
There's nothing to get off with! He's innocent!
我换个说法 你认为陪审团会宣告他无罪 是吗
I'll rephrase that. You think a jury will acquit him, right?
他一直在车里待着 甚至没有靠近过犯罪现场
He stayed in the car, wasn't even near the scene of the crime.
所以绝不可能有罪 对吗 对的 错
So therefore can't possibly be guilty, right? Right. Wrong!
约翰乔比任何人都要无辜
There's people less guilty than Johnjo doing life.
你知道这个合谋的法律是关于什么的吗
Do you know what this law's about, this Joint Enterprise Law?
它跟无辜与否无关
It's not about innocent or guilty,
而是将那些渣滓从大街上清除掉
it's about getting working class scum off the streets.
这也是他们对于我们孩子的看法 渣滓
That's how they see our kids - scum,
游手好闲的家伙 你的儿子 我的儿子
scallies. Your son, my son...
我去关门
I'm shutting this door.
吉莱斯皮和麦凯布 他们都会活下去
Gillespie and McCabe, they'll all get life...
我去关门 你别说了 听我说完
I'm shutting this door. You're not. You're going to hear me out.
到电脑上去搜搜
Put it into your laptop.
合谋团伙作案 看看你搜到些什么
Joint Enterprise and see what you get. Loads and...
把你的手从我的门上拿开
Get your hands off my door!
有很多无辜的孩子 还有很多更无辜的孩子
..Loads of innocent kids, twice as innocent as...
把你的手从门把上拿开 约翰乔和他们都能活下去
Get your hands off my door! ..Johnjo and they're all doing life.
我只是帮他们望风 其他什么都没做
All I did was watch my mate's back. That's all I did.
因为这样而被判6年已经够糟了
And it's bad enough getting six years for that,
所以 约翰乔 如果我能活下去也是特么的操蛋
so I'm fucked if I'm going to get life, Johnjo.
你会得到很好的照顾
You'll be well looked after.
约翰乔 你他妈的到底听着没
Johnjo, are you fucking listening?
我知道你必须
I know you've got to do
有一年自己孤零零待在监狱里当个少年犯
a year on your own at the young offenders'.
你跟我们没办法待在一起 你太小了
You can't be with us because of your age.
但是之后 我保证
But after that, I promise you,
你会跟我们待在一起
you'll be with us.
我在监狱里遇到任何一个人
Every fucking prison I go
我都会跟他们说你的事情的 草
in I'm gonna tell them about you, you cunt!
约翰乔 好好待上6年
Take the six, Johnjo.
你这个下流的白痴 臭烘烘的笨蛋家伙
You dirty, shithead, stinking arsed grass.
低声下气 这就是你要做的
Eyes in the back of your head, that's what you're going to need.
承认你对他人造成严重伤害吧 约翰乔
Plead guilty to GBH, Johnjo...
你知道我们对一个杂种的家庭会做什么吗
You know what we do to a grass' family?
告诉他们你对他人造成了严重伤害 我们收拾狗杂种
Tell them you'll take the GBH! We torch the bastards!
告诉他们你对他人造成严重伤害 约翰乔 你死定了
Tell them you'll take the GBH. Johnjo. You're dead!
约翰乔 告诉他们你会去坐牢
Johnjo! Tell them you'll take the fucking GBH.
他们一定会全都发火的
They're all going to fucking burn.
我知道你能听见 听我说 伙计
I know you can hear me! Listen to me, mate.
坐牢吧 我会去该死的 约翰乔
Take the GBH. I'm going to fucking... Johnjo!
他有血友病
He's a haemophiliac.
我们对他太过纵容了  一直都把他呵护在掌心里
We've mollycoddled him, wrapped him in cotton wool all his life.
你觉得他在监狱里待够6年还能活下来么
You think he'll survive six years in prison?
那可不是6年而已 他会被挑刺
It won't be six years. He'll get picked on,
被欺负 你知道会这样的
bullied, you know he will.
对我儿子来说 这6年可跟别人的6年不同
Six years for my son is not the same as six years for the others.
这6年可能代表着生死
Six years for my son might as well be life
所以我们不会认罪
so we're pleading not guilty.
好吧 那样的话我没办法替他辩护了
Well, in that case I can no longer represent him.
什么
What?!
为什么不是披萨店经理跟他们一同受审呢
Why isn't the pizza manager standing trial with them?
因为他们需要他的陈词
Because they needed his statement.
他们付出的代价是他的自由
The price they paid was his freedom.
他们需要约翰乔的陈词
They needed Johnjo's statement.
是啊 但是他随便就放弃了他
Yes. But he gave his away for nothing.
哦 你意思是说他很诚实 你完全错了 诚实就是个大错
Oh, he was honest, you mean. A big mistake, being honest.
嗯 这件事跟约翰乔完全没关系
Yes. It's nothing to do with Johnjo, this.
你不想失败 你不想别人看到你失败
You don't want to lose. You don't want to be seen to lose.
奥谢夫人 我只关心约翰乔
Mrs O'Shea, I care only for Johnjo.
如果我们拼了却输了 他能活下去
If we fight and lose, he gets life.
如果我们认罪了
If we plead guilty,
最糟的话 他要坐5年4个月的牢
the worst scenario is five years and four months.
不是6年 是5年4个月
Not six years, five years and four months.
最好的情况 他今天跟你一起回家
The best scenario - he comes home with you today.
基兰 吉莱斯皮 你被指控谋杀
Kieran Gillespie, you are charged with the murder
托马斯 詹姆斯 沃德 你有什么要说的吗
of Thomas James Ward. How do you plead?
我认罪
Guilty.
科林 麦凯布 你被指控同谋
Colin McCabe, you are charged with conspiracy to commit
并对他人造成严重伤害 你有什么要说的吗
grievous bodily harm. How do you plead?
认罪
Guilty.
安东尼 华莱士 你被指控同谋
Anthony Wallace, you are charged with conspiracy to
并对他人造成严重伤害 你有什么要说的吗
commit grievous bodily harm. How do you plead?
认罪
Guilty.
约翰 约瑟夫 奥谢
John Joseph O'Shea,
你被指控同谋并对他人造成严重伤害
you are charged with conspiracy to commit grievous bodily harm.
你有什么要说的吗
How do you plead?
认罪
Guilty.
你们可以就坐了
You may be seated.
基兰 吉莱斯皮 因你的罪行 判你25年起刑
'Kieran Gillespie, I take 25 years as a starting point.'
因有计划的袭击 再加两年
I add two for the planned nature of the attack,
另因团伙犯罪 再加两年
two for the fact that it was a group attack
另因受害者的脆弱 再加两年
and two years for the vulnerability of the victim.
由于无意杀害他人 减去三年
I deduct three years for the absence of an intention to kill,
再因主动认罪 减去两年
two years for your plea of guilty
再因缺乏父母教育 减去两年
and two years for the lack of parental guidance.
基兰 吉莱斯皮 你被判处
Kieran Gillespie, you are
至少24年有期徒刑
to be detained at her Majesty's pleasure
等待女王发落
for a minimum term of 24 years...
科林 麦凯布和安东尼 华莱士
Colin McCabe and Anthony Wallace,
你们两人被分别判处十年起刑
in each of your cases I start at ten years.
因你们之前良好的品格 减去一年
I will deduct one year for your previous good characters
再因你们主动认罪 减去三分之一
and allow the full one-third discount for your guilty pleas.
科林 麦凯布和安东尼 华莱士
Colin McCabe and Anthony Wallace,
你们两人被分别判处六年有期徒刑
you will each go to prison for six years.
约翰 约瑟夫 奥谢
John Joseph O'Shea,
因你犯罪时只有17岁
you were 17 at the time of the offences
我判处你八年起刑
and I therefore start at eight years.
因主动认罪 减刑三分之一
I will deduct a full one-third for your guilty plea
遵从刑事法庭法案授予我的权力
and I sentence you, under the Power of the Criminal Court Act,
判处你5年4个月有期徒刑
to five years and four months' detention.
请把他们带下去
Take them down, please.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
你们还好吧
You all right?
看到你很高兴
Good to see you.
你怎么样 很好
How are you? Great.
是吗 是的 真的
Yeah? Yeah. Honest.
没什么好担心的 他们是一群好小伙子
Nothing to worry about in here, they're a great bunch of lads.
他们让你一个人待着
They leaving you alone?
是啊
Yeah!
他们知道我有血友病
They know I'm haemophiliac,
他们知道如果碰了我 就可以弄死我
they know if they touch me, then they can kill me.
就像穿着一件盔甲什么的
It's like walking around with a suit of armour on or something!
妈妈 我很好 真的
Mum, I'm fine. Honestly.
对吗 我很好
Right? I'm fine.
有一点无聊 一切都是
It's just a bit boring, that's all.
你看到律师了吗
Did you see the lawyer?
是的 所以
Yeah. And?
约翰乔 他什么都做不了
There's nothing he can do, Jonjo.
我知道 他说了他会想尽办法的
He said he was going to do all sorts. I know.
伙同犯罪这个罪名是错的 需要被改变
"Joint enterprise is wrong, joint enterprise needs changing,
伙同犯罪这样 伙同犯罪那样
"Joint enterprise this, joint enterprise that."
你不是个伙同犯罪 儿子
You're not joint enterprise, son.
什么
What?
你对其他一些什么东西认罪了
You pleaded guilty to something else.
甚至不是一个审判
It wasn't even a trial.
我认罪只是因为害怕被判为同谋
I only pleaded guilty because I was scared of joint enterprise.
我知道
I know.
我们现在没什么能做的了
There's nothing we can do about it now.
哦 好吧
Oh, well!
你的邻居说你见过他 是的
Your neighbour said you'd been to see him. Yeah.
他怎么样
How is he?
他很好
Fine.
还能撑住么
Coping?
我觉得不能
I don't think so.
他假装是那样 但是我觉得不是
He pretends he is but I don't think he is.
你呢
And you?
实际上 沃德太太 我真为你感到骄傲
Actually, Mrs Ward, I'm really proud of him.
我一直觉得他让我骄傲
I always thought he'd make
从他拿到学位或者其他什么的开始
me proud by getting a degree or something
但是他要坐5年半的牢 还有血友病
but he's doing five and a half years and he's got haemophilia
而且他所在乎的只是不能让我失望
and all he cares about is not upsetting me
我觉得真
and I think that is so...
我觉得真他娘的勇敢
I think that is so fucking brave.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没事
It's OK.
我知道你爱着你的儿子
I know you'd love your
他要坐5年半的牢 但是
son to be doing five and a half years but...
你能告诉他 我收到他的信了吗
Could you tell him I got his letter?
他的信
His letter?
他给我写的
He wrote to me.
你不知道
You didn't know?
你想看看吗
Would you like to see it?
是的
Yes.
亲爱的沃德太太 我是在审判结束后写这封信的
"Dear Mrs Ward, I'm writing this after getting sentenced
因为我不想让你觉得
"Because I don't want you to think
我写信是为了让法官轻判我什么的
I'm only writing so the judge will go easy on me.
我以为我们是去吃披萨 沃德太太 真的
"I thought we were going for a pizza, Mrs Ward, honest.
但是我发现 这并不能让我变得无辜
"But I've realised that doesn't make me innocent.
看 如果我没有出生过
"See, if I hadn't had been born,
就不能开车载他们
"I wouldn't have been able to drive them,
你家托马斯就会还活着
and your Thomas would still be alive.
所以这也是一种罪
"So that's kind of a guilt.
并不是犯罪的罪 而是一种因无知而产生的罪
"It's not really a guilty guilt, it's more of an innocent guilt
但是一样有罪
"But it's a guilt just the same
这样在牢里过5年半 就会比
"And it's easier to do five and a half years thinking like that
我一直想着自己是无辜的 要好过得多
"Than five and a half years thinking I'm innocent.
我真的很抱歉 沃德太太
"I'm really sorry, Mrs Ward.
真的 真的很抱歉
"I'm really, really sorry."
你相信他吗
Do you believe him?
是的
Yes.
我儿子乔丹因合伙谋杀
My son Jordan is serving a 12 year minimum life sentence
被判处至少12年有期徒刑
for joint enterprise murder.
我姐姐劳拉 因合伙谋杀
My sister Laura was given 13 years 6 month sentence
被判处13年零6个月
for joint enterprise murder.
我兄弟迈克尔 霍尔因合伙谋杀
My brother Michael Hall was given 13 years 6 months
被判处13年零6个月
for joint enterprise murder.
他才15岁
He was 15.